Rhoades mss., LMC 2063
Lilly Library
Rhoades mss.
1933-1992
Lilly Library
Rhoades, Marcus M., 1903-1991.
LMC 2063
14 Boxes
Consists of the papers of geneticist Marcus C. Morton Rhoades.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift. 1990, 1992
Biographical Note
Rhoades earned his Bachelor and Master of Science degrees at the University of Michigan, and his doctorate at Cornell, specializing in corn genetics. He began his professional career as an associate geneticist at the United States Department of Agriculture where he did research on plant breeding from 1935-1940. In 1940 he returned to academia as an associate professor at Columbia University. In 1948 he was appointed Professor of Botany at the University of Illinois, then came to Indiana University where he chaired the Botany Department from 1958 until 1968. He was appointed Distinguished Professor Emeritus in 1974 and continued his studies in corn genetics until shortly before his death.
Scope and Content Note
The correspondence covers Rhoades's career and includes letters with many renowned geneticists. In addition to correspondence, the papers contain: research data and writings, career-related papers both inside and outside his academic appointments, including his work in scientific organizations and conferences and on various editorial boards, and a group of materials concerning colleague and Nobel prize winner Barbara McClintock.
Arrangement/Organization
The collection is organized into the following series: I. General correspondence; II. Research and writings; III. Appointments; IV. Classes; V. Committees; VI. Conferences and organizations; VII. Editorial boards; VIII. Grants; IX. Jones patent; X. McClintock; XI. Photographs; and, XII. Printed.
Rhoades, Marcus M. (Marcus Morton), 1903-1991.; McClintock, Barbara, 1902-; Corn --Genetics.; Genetics --Research --United States.; Indiana University; Science; McClintock, Barbara, 1902-
- General Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  Additional correspondence can be found throughout the collection. The correspondence is not indexed.
  - 1933-1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961-1974 (Box 2)
  - 1975-1992 (Box 3)
- Research and writings
  - By Rhoades
    - Abnormal chromosome 10 (Box 3, Folder 27-34)
    - Asynchronous replication of heterochromatin in maize (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
    - Biographical memoir of Rollins Adams Emerson, 1873-1947 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - The cell, vol. III: Meiosis chapter (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - Centromeres (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Chromatin elimination induced by the B chromosome of maize (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Chromosome elimination in maize (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Chromosome linkage data (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chromosome structure (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chromosomes, mutations, and cytoplasm in maize (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Cytogenetic studies on preferential segregation in maize, K 10 and K 3 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - A cytogenetic study of a chromosome fragment in maize (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - The cytogenetics of maize (Box 4, Folder 13-17)
    - Cytogenetics paper for maize symposium at Urbana (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Df 3b (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Different rates of crossing over in male and female gametes in maize (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Duplicate genes in maize (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The early years of maize genetics (Box 4, Folder 22-25)
    - The effect of abnormal chromosome 10 on preferential segregation and crossing over in maize (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Effect of the Dt gene on the mutability of the allele in maize (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
    - The effect of varying gene dosage on aleurone color in maize (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Elongate (Box 5, Folder 5-9)
    - The function and structure of the parenchyma sheath plastids of the maize leaf, by MMR and Alcides Carvalho (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Genetic and molecular charaterization of a-mrh - Mrh (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
    - Genetic nomenclature in maize (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Genetic studies with factors in the tenth chromosome in maize (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The golden age of corn genetics at Cornell (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Handbook of plant physiology (Box 5, Folder 17-22)
    - A highly repeated DNA sequence [and] Asynchronous replication of heterochromatin in maize (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - [A history of maize genetics] (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Hybrid corn (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Inversion 3a (Box 5, Folder 26-29)
    - Inversion 3a (cont'd) (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Inversion yield test (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - K10-I and K10-II (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
    - The lengths of the genetic maps in maize (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Lewis John Stadler, 1896-1954 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - Linkage summary (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Number 5 fragment (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - On the mechanism of chromatic loss induced by the B chromosome in maize (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
    - Origin and consequences of chromosome rearrangement (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Origin of cytoplasmic male sterility in corn (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Outline of proposed genetic and biochemical research on the effects of the shrunken factor (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Paramutation and gene conversion (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - A possible method for locating favorable genes in maize (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - A possible relationship between heterochromatin and mutation in maize (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Repeated DNA limited to knob heterochromatin in maize (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Secondary trisome (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Studies on the cytological basis of crossing over (Box 5, Folder 24-26)
    - Yield test calculations (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous book reviews (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous research (Box 5, Folder 29-34)
  - Reprints: Authored or co-authored by Rhoades.
    General
    Reprints are hand-numbered and arranged numerically.
    - 3. The frequencies of homozygosis of factors in attached-X females of Drosophila melanogaster (Genetics, 16:375-385, July ), 1931 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 4. A new type of translocation in Drosophila melanogaster (Genetics 16:490-504, ), Sept. 1931 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 8. Relation of chromatic crossing over to the upper limit of recombination percentages (The American Naturalist, Vol. LXVII, ), July-Aug. 1933 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 9. An experimental and theoretical study of chromatic crossing over (Genetics, 18:535-555, ), Nov. 1933 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 13. Rhoades and Joe L. Robinson. The 1935 Iowa corn yield test (Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 343), Feb. 1936 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 15. Note on the origin of triploidy in maize (Journal of Genetics, Vol. XXXIII, no. 3, pp. 355-357, ), Dec. 1936 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 16. The effect of varying gene dosage on aleurone colour in maize (Journal of Genetics, Vol. XXXIII, no. 3, pp. 347-354, ), Dec. 1936 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 20. Effect of the Dt gene on the mutability of the a1 allele in maize (Genetics 23:377-397, ), July 1938 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 21. Rhoades and Th. Dobzhansky. A possible method for locating favorable genes in maize (Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 30, no. 8, ), Aug. 1938 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 23. Maize genetics cooperation, VI. White sheath-3 (Genetics 24:62-63, ), 1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 24. Rhoades and Virginia H. Rhoades. Genetic studies with factors in the tenth chromosome in maize (Genetics 24:302-314, ), Mar. 1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 26. The genetic control of mutability in maize (Cold Spring Harbor Symposia on Quantitative Biology, 9:138-144), 1941 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 27. Different rates of crossing over in male and female gametes of maize (Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 33, no. 7, ), July 1941 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 28. Preferential segregation in maize (Genetics 27:395-407, ), July 1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 29. Rhoades and Hilda Vilkomerson. On the anaphase movement of chromosomes (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 28, no. 10, pp. 433-436, ), Oct. 1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 30. Genic induction of an inherited cytoplasmic difference (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 29, no. 11, pp. 327-329, ), Dec. 1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 32. On the genetic control of mutability in maize (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 31, no. 3, pp. 91-95, ), Mar. 1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 34. Crossover chromosomes in unreduced gametes of asynaptic maize (Records of Genetics Society of America, No. 15, p. 64), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 35. Plastic mutations (Cold Spring Harbor Symposia on Quantitative Biology, 11:202-207), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 38. Les plastes (Extract from Unités Biologiques Douées de Continuité Génétique, 1949, pp. 37-44) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 39. Meiosis in maize (Journal of Heredity, Vol. XLI, no. 3, ), Mar. 1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 40. Gene induced mutation of a heritable cytoplasmic factor producing male sterility in maize (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 36, no. 11, pp. 634-635, ), Nov. 1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 42. Duplicate genes in maize (The American Naturalist, Vol. LXXXV, ), Mar.-Apr. 1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 46. Comments on the paper "Photographs of living chromosomes." (Journal of Heredity, Vol. XLV, no. 1, ), Jan.-Feb. 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 47. Chromosomes, mutations, and cytoplasm in maize (Science,, Vol. 120, no. 3108, pp.115-120), July 23, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 48. Lewis J. Stadler, geneticist (Science,, Vol. 120, no. 3119, pp. 553-554), Oct. 8, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 49. Interaction of genic and non-genic hereditary units and the physiology of non-genic inheritance (Handbuch der pflanzenphysiologie, Vol. 1) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 52. Chapter 1: Meiosis (The Cell, Vol. III, Academic Press Inc.: New York and London) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 53. Unusual events in seed development Yearbook of Agriculture, U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1961, pp. 75-79) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 54. Discussion of session I (Mutation and Plant Breeding, NAS-NRC 891,, pp. 48-51), 1961 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 55. Rhoades and Ellen Dempsey. The effect of abnormal chromosome 10 on preferential segregation and crossing over in maize (Genetics, Vol. 53, No. 5, ), May, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 56. Induction of chromosome doubling at meiosis by the elongate gene in maize (Genetics, Vol. 54, No. 2, ), Aug. 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 57. Rhoades and Ellen Dempsey and Achille Ghidoni. Chromosome elimination in maize induced by supernumerary B chromosomes (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 57, no. 6, pp. 1626-1632, ), June 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 58. Studies on the cytological basis of crossing over (Replication and Recombination of Genetic Material, edited by W.J. Peacock and R.D. Brock, Australian Academy of Science: Canberra, ), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 59. Rhoades and Ellen Dempsey. On the mechanism of chromatic loss induced by the B chromosome of maize (Genetics 71:73-96, ), May 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 62. A portrait of E.G.Anderson, 1891-1973 (Stadler Symposium, Vol. 5, pp. 9-12, University of Missouri, Columbia) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 63. Rhoades and Ellen Dempsey. Cytogenetic studies on a transissible deficiency in chromosome 3 of maize (Journal of Heredity, Vol. 64, no. 3, ), May-June, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 64. Rhoades and Ellen Dempsey. Chromatin elimination induced by the B chromosome of maize (Journal of Heredity, Vol. 64, no. 1, ), Jan.-Feb., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 67. Chapter 40: Genetic effects of heterochromatin in maize (Maize Breeding and Genetics, ed. by David B. Walden, John Wiley & Sons, Inc.:n.p., ), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 69. Rhoades and A. Pryor, K. Faulkner and W.J. Peacock. Asynchronous replication of heterochromatin in maize (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 77, no. 11, pp. 6705-6709, ), Nov. 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 70. Rhoades and W.J. Peacock, E.S. Dennis and A.J. Pryor. Highly repeated DNA sequence limited to knob heterochromatin in maize (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 78, no. 7, pp. 4490-4494, ), July 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 71. The early years of maize genetics (Annual Review of Genetics,, 18:1-29), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 72. Rhoades and Ellen Dempsey. Structural heterogeneity of chromosome 10 in races of maize and teosinte (Plant Genetics, Alan R. Liss, Inc.: n.p.,, pp. 1-18), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 73. Barbara McClintock: An appreciation (Maydica XXXI, :1-4), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 74. Genetic and molecular characterization of a-mrh-Mrh, a new mutable system of Zea mays (Developmental Genetics 10:507-519, ), 1989 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Research and writings by others.
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    See also: Editorial boards; Printed
    - de Toledo Piza, S. Chromosomes of the scorpion tityus bahiensis perty (English abstract of 4 articles) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Dobzhansky, Th. [Account of trip to Brazil, 1949] (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Gurgel, J.T.A. The non-homologous associations of centromeres and knobs of maize chromosomes at meiosis (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Kwen-Sheng Chiang. Physical conservation of parental cytoplasmic DNA through meiosis in Chlamydomonas reinhardi (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Li, H.W. and Y.H. Chang. Non-synchronization of the movement of the chromosomal sets and other abnormalities in the amphidiploids in Triticinae (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Mazoti, Lius B. New discoveries about the behaviour of the units of heredity genes and plasmons (abstract) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Patterson, E.B. Proposed procedures for the use of genic male sterility in hybrid maize production (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Rhoades, Virginia H. The location of a gene for disease resistance in maize (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Schultz, Jack. Characteristics of pairing in the salivary gland chromosomes of Drosophila melanogaster (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Schwartz, Drew. The genetics of bacteriophage (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Sonneborn, Tracy M. Experimental control of the concentration of cytoplasmic genetic factors in paramecium (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Appointments
  Includes materials relating to Rhoades's position at the United States Department of Agriculture and his various university appointments. Arranged in chronological order.
  - United States Department of Agriculture. Arlington Farm, Virginia, 1935-1940 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Columbia University, 1940-1948 (Box 7, Folder 15-16)
  - University of Illinois, 1948-1958 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Indiana University, 1958-1968 (Box 7, Folder 18-31)
- Classes
  Includes notes, tests, etc. pertaining to classes Rhoades attended and those he taught. Arranged alphabetically by subject or title of class.
  - Accidents of meiosis (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Apomixis (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Bacteriology 405 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Botany 31 (1925) (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Botany 201-202 (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
  - Botany 320 - Cytology (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Centromere (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Chemical induction of mutation (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Chromosome structure (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Chromosome structure, composition and replication (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Crossing over (Box 8, Folder 3-7)
  - Cytogenetics, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cytogenetics, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Cytology, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Cytology, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Embryo sac development (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Endomitosis (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Evolution of chromosome form and number (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Gene and cytoplasm, iojap and plastids (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Genetics 101 - University of California (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Genetics 530 - Iowa State College 1934 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Genic control (Ds-Ac) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Heterochromatin (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Inversions (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Meiosis (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Meiotic drive (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Microtechnique (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Mitosis (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Molecular genetics (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Mutation (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Mutation Ac Ds (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Mutation Dt gene (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Mutation Rr, Ab (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Neurospora crossing over (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Nucleolus (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Pericentric inversions (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Polyploidy (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Position effect (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Recombination - centromere (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Sex determination (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Sister strand crossing over (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Somatic crossing over (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Temperature-moisture-time complex (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Translocations (Box 8, Folder 40-42)
  - Unequal crossing over (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Unusual genetic mechanisms (Box 8, Folder 44)
- Committees
  Committees served on by Rhoades at universities and institutes outside his full-time appointments. Includes materials concerning personnel selection and reviews of departments.
  - Brookhaven National Lab, visiting committee, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cornell University, Biology Studies, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 2-7)
  - Harvard University, Department of Biology, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Harvard University, faculty appointment, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - University of Copenhagen, faculty appointment, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - University of Rochester, training grant renewal, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - University of Vermont, Department of Plant and Soil, and Department of Botany, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Conferences and organizations
  - Agricultural Research Service, information kit (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Allerton meeting, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - American Genetic Association, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - American Society of Naturalists, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Biology Research Conference on Chromosome Mechanics at the Molecular Level, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Apr. 10-13, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Botanical Society of America, Hoblitzelle National Award, 1957-1965 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Genetics, Inc., 1939-1962 (Box 9, Folder 21-23)
  - Genetics Society of America, 1941-1980 (Box 9, Folder 24-25)
  - Genetics Society of America (con't), 1941-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
  - Guggenheim, 1964-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
  - Hybrid Corn Industry Conference, Nov. 28-29, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - International Committee on Genetic Symbols and Nomenclature, 1954-1973 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - International Conference on Replication and Recombination of Genetic Material, Canberra, Australia, Aug. 28-Sept. 1, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - International Congress of Genetics - Exhibition, Scotland, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - International Genetics Symposia, Japan, Sept. 6-12, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - International Maize Symposium, University of Illinois, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Methodology in Medical Genetics symposium, Austin, Texas, May 3-5, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - National Academy of Sciences, Joseph Henry Fund, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - National Institutes of Health, Division of Research Grants applications, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - National Institutes of Health, Fundamental Genetics proposal, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - National Research Council, Division of Biology and Agriculture, 1942-1967 (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
  - National Science Foundation: reports of meetings, National Medal of Science award, and proposals, 1962-1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - National Science Foundation: reports of meetings, National Medal of Science award, and proposals (con't), 1962-1981 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
  - Stadler Genetics Symposium, University of Missouri-Columbia, Apr. 13-14, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Unités Biologiques Douées de Continuité Génétique, Paris, June 25-July 3, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Editorial boards
  Includes correspondence, critiques and reviews by Rhoades and others, as well as the papers submitted for publication in the following journals: Caryologia, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, and Science.
  - Caryologia
    - Correspondence and critiques (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences
    Includes critiques, correspondence and manuscripts. Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Alleman, Mary and Michael Freeling. The Mu transposable element of maize: Evidence for transposition and copy number regulation during development (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Ausich, Rodney L. and Rose M. Murphy. Infection of Chlamydomonas reinhardtii by Agrobacterium tumefaciens (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Blamire, John, Valerie R. Flechtner, and Ruth Sager. Regulation of nuclear DNA replication by the chloroplast in Chlamydomonas (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Blumenthal, Thomas, James Douglass and Daniel Smith. Conformational alteration of protein synthesis elongation factor EF-Tu by EF-Ts and by kirromycin (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Boynton, J. E., W. G. Burton, N. G. Gillham, and E. H. Harris. Can a mom-Mendelian mutation affect both chloroplasts and mitochondrial ribosome? (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Brewen, J. G., and W. J. Peacock. Restricted rejoining of chromosomal subunits in aberration formation: A test for subunit dissimilarity. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Crandall, Marjorie, Lawrence M. Lawrence, and Robert M. Saunders. Molecular complementarity of yeast glycoprotein mating factors. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Drets, Maximo E., and Margery W. Shaw. Specific banding patterns of human chromosomes. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Ferl, Robert J. and Drew Schwartz. Mutations of maize alcohol dehydrogenase-l isozymes which influence electrophoretic mobility in the presence of sodium dodecyl sulfate (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Forest, Charlene L. and Robert K. Togasaki. Selection for conditional gametogenesis in Chlamydomonas reinhardi. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Goldstein, David J., Robert K. Naviaux, Mary M. Davis, M. Edward Hodes and Thomas M. Ulbright. Pancreatic amylase specific monoclonal antibody binds salivary gland ducts (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Helentjaris, Tim, David F. Weber, and Scott Wright. Use of monosomics to map cloned DNA fragments in maize (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Lemieux, Claude, Monique Turmel, Verner L. Seligy and Robert W. Lee. Chloroplast DNA recombination in interspecific hybrids of Chlamydomonas. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Lien, Stephen, Anthony San Pietro, and Howard Gest. Mutational and physiological enhancement of photosynthetic energy-conversion in Rhodopseudomonas capsulata (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Lowery-Goldhammer, Carolyn and John P. Richardson. An RNA-dependent nucleoside triphosphate phosphohydrolase (ATPase) associated with Rho termination factor. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Mahler, Henry R. and Karl Dawidowicz. Autonomy of mitochondria of Saccharomyces cerevisiae in their production of messenger RNA. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Marvo, Sandra L., Steven R. King, and S. Richard Jaskunas. The role of short regions of homology in intermolecular illegitimate recombinations. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Miller, Carlos O. Cytokinin inhibition of electron transport in mitochondria (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Miller, Carlos O. Zeatin ribonucleoside: A major cytokinin produced by crown gall tumor tissue (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Newton, Kathleen J. and Virginia Walbot. Maize mitochondria synthesize organ-specific polypeptides. (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Paul, Anna-Lisa, Vimla Vasil, Indra K. Vasil and Robert J. Ferl. Constitutive and anaerobically induced DNase-I hypersensitive sites in the 5' region of the maize Adh1 gene (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Peralta, Ernest G. and Lloyd Walter Ream. T-DNA border sequences required for crown gall tumorigenesis. (Box 11, Folder 30)